Guide to the Edward S. Goldstein: Jewish Labor Committee Research Files WAG.232
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Edward S. Goldstein: Jewish Labor Committee Research Files
1933-1985
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Goldstein, Edward Samuel
Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.)
WAG.232
5.25 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Edward Samuel Goldstein (1944- ) taught U.S. history in the Boston area and later went on to a career in the telecommunications industry. In the mid-1970s he began research toward a dissertation at Brandeis University on the history of the Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.). He secured the cooperation of the Jewish Labor Committee and its then-executive director, Emanuel Muravchik, and was given access to the organization's files. The dissertation was never finished, but Goldstein completed a considerable amount of research, and composed several draft chapters. This collection is comprised of notes, drafts, original documents, correspondence, photocopies accumulated by Goldstein in the course of his work on this project, as well as other material dealing with his interests in twentieth-century American Jewish history. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Custodial History
The files were sent by Edward S. Goldstein to the Jewish Labor Committee in 2002, and donated by the Committee to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, NYU in the same year.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Edward Samuel Goldstein (1944- ) of Newton, MA earned degrees from Hebrew College, Harvard University, New York University and the University of Michigan. In the mid-1970s he embarked on research toward a Ph.D. degree at Brandeis University; his intention was to write a dissertation on the history of the Jewish Labor Committee, 1934-1967, under the direction of Professors Ben Halpern and Marshall Sklare. The project employed the methodology of sociological historiography exemplified by the work of Professor Halpern and Israeli historian Jacob Katz. Goldstein described the dissertation as "an analytic history of the Jewish Labor Committee, involving questions of social and ideological change amongst Jews and policymaking in the American labor movement." While pursuing his Ph.D., he taught at Clark University and Anna Maria College.
Goldstein secured the cooperation of the Jewish Labor Committee and its then Executive Director, Emanuel Muravchik, and was given access to extensive files of records stored at the JLC office in New York City. He made photocopies of many items and acquired original documents which were duplicates. In addition, he accumulated a considerable amount of research material and notes derived from other sources, both archival and printed. These materials, along with related correspondence, several draft chapters and a paper presented at the 1978 meeting of the American Jewish Studies Association, comprise the bulk of this collection.
The official records of the Jewish Labor Committee were donated to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives in 1985. By this time, some of the documents consulted and copied by Goldstein in earlier years had been lost. Thus, his collection fills important gaps in JLC history, and further enriches the Library's holdings on the subject by adding Goldstein's own writings and notes, as well as research materials from non-JLC sources.
Goldstein left academic pursuits in 1980, with the dissertation unfinished. He was employed for many years as an executive in the telecommunications industry, and in 2004 served as divisional vice-president in the Eastern United States for Charter Communications, a major national broadband and cable television provider. The JLC research material remained, undisturbed, in his possession until it was presented to the Jewish Labor Committee in 2002.
Scope and Content Note
Series I: Edward Goldstein: Writings and Notes, c.1967-1980, includes drafts of several chapters of Goldstein's dissertation-in-progress on the history of the Jewish Labor Committee; a Dissertation Plan, submitted to Brandeis University; a paper giving an overview of the dissertation topic, presented to the American Jewish Studies Association in 1978; and folders of notes relating to key themes, persons and events in JLC history.
Series II: Subject Files, 1933-1985, includes files of correspondence, notes, clippings, original documents and photocopies of documents relating to important aspects of JLC history, such as anti-Nazi activity, anti-Communism, aid to refugees and displaced person, work in the U.S. labor and civil rights movements, attitudes toward and work in Palestine and Israel, campaigns on behalf of Soviet Jewry, and relations with other Jewish communal organizations and labor organizations. In addition to material that clearly relates to Goldstein's research on the Jewish Labor Committee, this series also contains a few files of correspondence, clippings, periodicals and documents illustrating his broader interests in twentieth-century Jewish history, culture and politics.
Series III: Oversized Item (Photocopied Scrapbook), 1942. A photocopy of a large clippings scrapbook, compiled in the JLC office, covering the year 1942. Included are clippings from the English and Yiddish press pertaining to JLC activities and issues of interest to the Committee. This scrapbook is one of a series, the rest of which can be found in the Records of the Jewish Labor Committee (Wagner 25).
NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Arrangement
Series I and II are arranged alphabetically by topic within each series; the Clippings Scrapbook comprising Series III is arranged chronologically.
The files are grouped into 3 series:
Missing Title
I: Edward Goldstein, Writings and Notes, c.1967-1980
II: Subject Files, 1933-1985
III: Oversized Item (Photocopied Scrapbook), 1942.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Papers of Julius Bernstein. Wagner 116.
Records of the Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.). Wagner 025.
Records of the Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.), Part II, Holocaust Era Files. Wagner 025.
Papers of Jacob Pat. Wagner 127.
Papers of Isaiah Minkoff. Wagner 086.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Jewish Labor Committee, 2002. The accession number associated with this gift is 2002.015.
Jewish refugees.; Clippings (information artifacts); Jews, Soviet.; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Notes.; Correspondence.; New York (N.Y.); Scrapbooks.; Fliers (printed matter); Minutes (administrative records); Jews |x Rescue.; Jews -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Anti-fascist movements -- United States.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Jews -- Rescue.; Drafts (documents); Muravchik, Emanuel, d. 2007; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.)
- Series I: Edward Goldstein, Writings and Notes, c.1967-1980.
  - Abstract and Overview (includes AJS paper), 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Communism/Soviet Jewry, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Background: Draft, Pages 1-42, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Background: Draft, Pages 43-140, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Background: Draft, Pages 141-232, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Background: Partial Draft, Pages 148-200, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Background: Partial Draft, Pages 201-250, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Background: Partial Draft, Pages 251-306, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Bridge to Labor": Draft Chapter, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights Sections, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Founding of the Jewish Labor Committee (JLC), undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Goldstein: Dissertation Plan, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Interviews: Lists and Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Jewish Labor Committee Assessments": Draft Chapter, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Labor Movement: General, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Labor Guild: School of Industrial Relations (Boston): Goldstein Course, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Reparations: Genocide Convention, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Vladeck, Baruch Charney, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Zionism and JLC, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1933-1985.
  - Administrative Committee: Membership, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Aid: Soviet Union, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Aid to Displaced Persons (JLC), 1949-1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Algerian Jews: Cremieux Law, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers: Support for JLC, 1950-1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Automobile Association: JLC Protest, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Federation of Labor (AFL) and American Federation of Labor/Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1947-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - AFL-CIO and Civil Rights, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - AFL-CIO Conference: JLC Commentary, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - AFL-CIO: Foreign Policy, 1949-1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - AFL-CIO Merger: JLC Role, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Jewish Committee/Anti-Defamation League/Jewish Labor Committee: Relations and Joint Activities, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Jewish Committee: History, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - American Jewish Committee and JLC: Relations, 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - American Jewish Committee: National Labor Service, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - American Jewish Conference, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - American Jewish Congress and Communists, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - American Jewish Congress and Communists: J. Marker M.A. Thesis, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - American Jewish Congress and Labor, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee/JLC Rivalry, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - American Jewish Labor Council, 1946-1953 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - American Labor Conference on International Affairs, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - American Labor: Resolution Addressed to the Oppressed People of Europe, 1943? (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Annual Reports: Drafts, 1947-1948, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Anti-Communism Without McCarthyism": Seminar, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Anti-Defamation League-JLC Relations, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Anti-Discrimination Work: Confidential Report, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Anti-Nazi Activity, 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Anti-Nazi Boycott, 1933-1938 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Anti-Semitism: United States, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Appleton, Shelley: Draft Speech, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Apprenticeship: Equal Opportunity Programs, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Archives (JLC), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Association of Federation Workers: Appeal to JLC, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Atran Center: Opening, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Atran House, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Austria: Plight of Bundists in Displaced Persons Camps, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Austrian Government and the Palestinian Liberation Organization (PLO), 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Baskin, Joseph, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Bermuda Conference, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Bernstein, Julius, 1954-1968 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Black Congressional Caucus, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Black Nationalism: New Politics Convention, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Blacks and Anti-Semitism, undated, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Blacks and Israel, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Blacks and Jews, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Bohm, William: Report on Social Democratic Party of Hungary, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Borovoy, A. Alan (Canada), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Boston, 1949-1967 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Bronx: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Brumberg, Joseph, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Budget, 1945-1974 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Budget: Federations, 1939-1977 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Budget: Field Offices, 1955-1974 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Building Trades and JLC, 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Cain, Harry P.: Resignation, undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Canada: JLC Reports, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Cap Makers Union, Local 2, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Casals, Pablo: Spanish Refugee Aid, undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Catholic Church and Anti-Semitism, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Catholic Church-JLC Relations, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Chemical Workers, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Chicago, 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Chicago: JLC Activity, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Chicago Welfare Fund: Budget Hearings, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Chicopee, Georgia and Organizing Drive: Racist Leaflet, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - "Child Adoption" Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Citrine, Walter: Speech to AFL, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Civil Rights Activities of the JLC and Labor, 1947-1968 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Civil Rights: Birmingham Rally, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Civil Rights: Muravchik Speech, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Civil Rights: Emmett Till Case, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cleveland, Ohio, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cleveland, Ohio: Discrimination in United Auto Workers, Local 1054, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cleveland, Ohio: Klein, Paul, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Clippings: JLC Activities, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Commission on the Role of the JLC in Jewish Life, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Committee to Combat Anti-Semitism, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Committee to Commemorate the Six Million Martyrs, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Common Cause, JLC Newsletter, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Communism: United States, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Communist-Oriented Jewish Organizations, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Communists and JLC, 1945-1955 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conference: JLC, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Confidential Newsletters, 1952-1958 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) and JLC, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CIO and JLC: Yiddish Text by J. Kissman?, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - CIO Press: Aronin/Motz Study, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Connecticut, 1947-1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Convention, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Convention, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Convention, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Convention (2), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Convention: Allocation of Delegates, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Convention: Planning, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Convention: Visa Arrangements, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Goldstein, E. S., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Council of the Underground Anti-Nazi Labor Movement in Europe, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Czechoslovakia: Political Situation, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Czechoslovakian Jewry, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - [no file with this number], undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - De Dominicis, Ulysee: Presentation to Lehman, H., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Delaware, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Detroit, 1949-1954 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Detroit: JLC Problems, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Detroit: Report, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Displaced Persons, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Displaced Persons: Garment and Millinery Workers Accepted by Canada, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Displaced Persons: Letter to Marshall, George C., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Displaced Persons: Norway: Haakon Lie Telegram, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Draft Resistance, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Dubinsky, David, 1947-1966 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - East European Jewry, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Eban Abba: Testimonial, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Epstein, Lasar, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Erlich-Alter Memorial, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - European Socialists: JLC Contracts, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Fair Employment Practices (FEPC), 1954 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Farm Workers: Grape Boycott, 1966-1978 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation and JLC, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Field Reports, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Film: "Crown of Glory", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Finances, 1948-1957 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Finances: Contributions to Jewish Organizations, ca.1940-1941? (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Finances: Jerry Wurf Letter, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Fisk University/JLC Project: Library and Bibliography, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Five Who Led, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - France and Belgium: Children's Homes and Other JLC-Supported Institutions, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - France: Cremieux Law, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - France: Mollet, Guy, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - French Socialists, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Friends of the JLC, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Fundraising: From Unions, 1949-1965 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Genesis 2, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Genocide Convention: Ad Hoc Committee, etc., 1951-1967 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Genocide Convention: Chinese Policy on, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Genocide Convention: JLC Support for, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - German-Americans: Anti-Semitism, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - German Socialists and Trade Unionists, 1952-1968 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Germany: Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD) Policy in Israel, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Gershman, Carl: "Social Democracy and U.S. Labor", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Godson, Joseph, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Goldmann, Nahum, Speech, Washington, DC, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Governmental Relations, 1946-1965 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Green, William, 1940-1951 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Green, William: Cable to Polish Trade Unions, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Green, William: Letter to Randolph, A. Philip, 1939-1949 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Gross, Feliks: Presentation and Discussion on Communist History, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Hall, Paul, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Hawaii, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Held, Adolph, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Held, Adolph: Aufbau article, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Held, Adolph: Tribute to Lehman, Herbert H.: Baltimore, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Held, Adolph: Tribute to Truman, Harry S.: Cleveland, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Hill, Herbert, undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Hill, Herbert vs. International Ladies= Garment Workers= Union and JLC, 1958-1973 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Holocaust: General, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Holocaust: JLC Book Proposal, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Hospital Workers, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Hotel Workers and JLC, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Hungary, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW), Local 3 and JLC, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - International Ladies= Garment Workers= Union (ILGWU), 1947-1967 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - ILGWU, Local 10, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Immigration, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Immigration Issues, 1944-1978 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Immigration: JLC Activities, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Indiana: Politics of United Auto Workers (UAW) Locals, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Institute on Jewish Affairs: JLC/Workmen's Circle, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Interim Committee, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - International Conference of Labor Organizations, undated (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - International Federation of Trade Unions, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - International Labor Committee on Post-War Problems, undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Iraqi Jews, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Israel, 1948-1958 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Israel and the Middle East, 1953-1978 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Israel: JLC Attitudes Toward, 1049 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Israel: JLC Projects, 1955-1968 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Israel: Meir, Golda, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Israel: U.S. Labor Support, 1955-1978 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Italian-American Labor Council, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - J.P. Stevens Boycott, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Jacobs, Sam: (UAW), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Jewish Labor Bund, 1937-1955 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - JLC Affiliates and Cooperating Organizations, undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - JLC Calendar, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - JLC Delegation to Europe and Israel: Report to U.S. State Department, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - JLC Educator, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - JLC News, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - "Jewish Problem in the American Trade Union Press": Study, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Jewish Resistance during the Holocaust, 1933-1939 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Jewish Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War: Notes and References, undated (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Jewish War Veterans, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Joint Policy and Planning Committee: JLC/ADL/AJC, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Judah L. Magnes Foundation, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Kaplan, Milton, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Kemsley, William, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr.: Letter on Anti-Semitism, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Kirschenbaum, Walter, 1952-1966 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Kirschenbaum, Walter: Political Correspondence, 1953-1961 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Kissman, Joseph, undated (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Kramer, Philip, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Kutzik, A.J.: "Structure of the American Jewish Community", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Labor and Civil Rights, 1949-1978 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Labor and Civil Rights: CIO Unions, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Labor and Civil Rights: Local Unions and Race, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Labor and Foreign Policy, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Labor Chest for the Liberation of Europe, 1934-1943 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Labor Committee for Human Rights, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Labor Conference to Stop Communist Aggression, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Labor Information Service, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Labor Reports: Study of Effectiveness, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Labor-Sponsored Films Project, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Labor Zionist Organizations: Admission to JLC, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Large City Budgeting Conference (JLC), 1954-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Large City Budgeting Conference: JLC Presentation, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1952-1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Liberal Party, 1955-1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Loans by JLC, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Local 1707 (CSAE): JLC Chapter, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Los Angeles, 1948-1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Los Angeles: Anti-JLC Publicity, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Louisiana, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lowenthal, Al: "Jewish Labor Then and Now", 1963 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Lyons, Eugene: Anti-Communist Book Project, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - MacIver Report, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Marshall, Thurgood, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - McCarthyism, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - McLaurin, Benjamin, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Meany, George, 1946-1967 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Meetings: JLC, 1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Membership Lists: JLC Bodies, 1943-1978 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Mendes-France, Pierre, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Middle East, 1956-1967 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Middle East Crisis, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Minkoff, Isaiah: Reports, Speeches, etc., 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1941-1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1950-1956 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1934-1950 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Minutes: Office Committee, 1939-1941 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Minutes: Office Committee, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Minutes: Office Committee, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Minutes: Office Committee, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Minutes: Office Committee, 1945-1949 (Box 3, Folder 42)